(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
I say...
START:DASH!!
作詞：畑 亜貴　作曲：佐々木 裕
Lyrics: Aki Hata / Composition: Yu Sasaki
Hey, Hey, Hey, START:DASH!!
産声の小鳥たちも
Even the newborn birds
いつか空に羽ばたく
Will one day take flight into the sky
大きな強い翼で飛ぶ
Flying with large, strong wings
あきらめちゃダメなんだ
You mustn't give up
その日が絶対来る
That day will surely come
君も感じてるよね
You feel it too, don't you?
始まりの鼓動
The pulse of a new beginning
明日よ変われ！
Change, O tomorrow!
希望に変われ！
Turn into hope!
眩しい光に照らされて変われ
Be illuminated by a dazzling light and change
START!!
悲しみに閉ざされて
Enclosed in sadness
泣くだけの君じゃない
You are not just someone who cries
熱い胸きっと未来を
With a passionate heart, surely the future...
切り拓くはずさ
...will be paved open
悲しみに閉ざされて
Enclosed in sadness
泣くだけじゃつまらない
Just crying is boring
きっと (きっと)
Surely (Surely)
君の夢のちから
The power of your dreams
いまを動かすちから
The power that moves the present
信じてるよ…だから START!
I believe in it... so START!
Hey, Hey, Hey, START:DASH!!
雨あがりの気分で
With the feeling of after the rain
高まる期待のなか
Amidst rising expectations
つまずいたことさえも
Even the times you stumbled
思い出にしよう
Let's turn them into memories
明日が咲くよ
Tomorrow will bloom
希望が咲くよ
Hope will bloom
楽しいメロディ口ずさみ咲いた
Humming a joyful melody, it bloomed
DASH!!
喜びを受け止めて
Accept the joy
君と僕つながろう
Let you and I be connected
迷い道 やっと外へ
Finally out of the maze
抜け出したはずさ
You should have escaped
喜びを受け止めて
Accept the joy
君と僕進むだろう
Let you and I move forward
それは (それは)
That is (That is)
遠い夢の欠片
A fragment of a distant dream
愛しい欠片
A precious fragment
彼方へと僕は DASH!
Toward the beyond, I DASH!
またひとつ
Yet another...
うぶげの... 夢が... 生まれ...
A fledgling... dream... is born...
悲しみに閉ざされて 泣くだけの君じゃない
You're not someone who just cries, shut in by sadness
熱い胸 きっと未来を 切り開くはずさ
With your burning heart, you will surely carve out a future
喜びを受け止めて 君と僕 つながろう
Accept the joy, let's connect, you and I
迷い道 あと少しで 抜け出したはずさ
You must have escaped that maze-like path by now
喜びを受け止めて 君と僕 進むだろう
Accept the joy, we will move forward together
それは 夢の欠片 愛おしい欠片
It's a fragment of a dream, a precious fragment
彼方へと 僕はだ...
To the beyond, I am...
Hey, Hey, Hey, START:DASH!!
羽ばたいたら 戻らないと言って
Say that if you spread your wings, you won't return
ブルーバード
作詞・作曲 水野良樹
Blue Bird
Lyrics & Composition: Yoshiki Mizuno
目指したのは 蒼い 蒼い あの空
What you aimed for was that blue, blue sky
悲しみはまだ覚えられず 切なさは今掴みはじめた
I still can't remember sadness, and I've just started to grasp pain
あなたへと抱くこの感情も 今言葉に変わっていく
Even these feelings I hold for you are now turning into words
未知なる世界の夢から目覚めて
Waking up from a dream of an unknown world
この羽を広げ 飛び立つ
Spread these wings and take flight
羽ばたいたら 戻らないと言って
Say that if you spread your wings, you won't return
目指したのは 白い 白い あの雲
What you aimed for was those white, white clouds
突き抜けたら みつかると知って
Knowing you'll find it if you break through
振り切るほど 蒼い 蒼い あの空
Blue, blue, that sky, enough to break free
蒼い 蒼い あの空
Blue, blue, that sky
愛想尽きたような音で 錆びれた古い窓は壊れた
With a sound like it's lost all affection, the rusty old window broke
見飽きたカゴは ほら捨てていく 振り返ることはもうない
Look, I'm throwing away the cage I'm tired of seeing; there's no looking back anymore
高鳴る鼓動に 呼吸をあずけて
Entrusting my breath to my throbbing heartbeat
この窓を蹴って 飛び立つ
Kick this window and take flight
駆け出したら 手にできると言って
Say that if I start running, I can grasp it
いざなうのは 遠い 遠い あの声
What beckons is that far, far-off voice
眩しすぎた あなたの手も握って
Holding your hand, which was far too dazzling
求めるほど 蒼い 蒼い あの空
The more I seek it, the blue, blue sky
堕ちていくと わかっていた
I knew I would fall
それでも 光を追い続けていくよ
Even so, I will keep chasing the light
羽ばたいたら 戻れないと言って
Say that if you spread your wings, you won't return
探したのは 白い 白い あの雲
What I searched for was those white, white clouds
突き抜けたら みつかると知って
Knowing you'll find it if you break through
振り切るほど 蒼い 蒼い あの空
Blue, blue, that sky, enough to break free
蒼い 蒼い あの空
Blue, blue, that sky
みんなー！こんらみー！
Everyone! Konlamy!
こんらみー！
Konlamy!
え、今日は雪花ラミィのバースデーライブに来てくれて、ありがとう！
Um, thank you for coming to Yukihana Lamy's Birthday Live today!
え、早速ですが、一曲目『スタートダッシュ』、
Um, to start things off, the first song was "Start Dash",
え、二曲目『ブルーバード』を聴いていただきました。
and the second song you heard was "Blue Bird".
みんな、どうだった？どうだった？
Everyone, how was it? How was it?
ラミィダンス頑張りました！みんなダンス見てくれた？
Lamy worked hard on the dancing! Did everyone see it?
みんな、頑張ったよ！ラミィ頑張ったよ！
Everyone, I worked hard! Lamy worked hard!
え、そしてですね、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！ジャジャン！
And also, here is today's hashtag! Ta-da!
#雪花ラミィバースデーライブとなっております！イェイイェイ！
It's #YukihanaLamyBirthdayLive! Yay yay!
今日はね、このハッシュタグをたくさんみんな呟いてもらえたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
I'd be happy if everyone tweeted a lot using this hashtag today. Thank you!
え、それでは、ここからはですね、ゲストと一緒に歌っていきたいと思います！
Well then, from here on, I'm going to sing together with guests!
あの先輩や、あの同期まで！
Including that senior, and even that genmate!
最後までホロたっぷりと、なっておりますので、みんな楽しみにしててね！
It's going to be packed with Holo until the very end, so please look forward to it!
え、そしてですね、最後には告知もありますので、ぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでいってください！
And also, there's an announcement at the end, so please enjoy yourselves until the very end!
それでは...んー、ま！
Well then... *kiss*
じょいふる
Joyful
君の声を聞かせて
Let me hear your voice
さあ冒険してみない？
Why don't we go on an adventure?
楽しいこと始めよう
Let's start something fun
遊びたい 絶対 遊びたい
I want to play, I absolutely want to play
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to 陽気な Baby
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to cheerful Baby
JOY to JOY to JOY to ハッピーな People
JOY to JOY to JOY to HAPPY People
弱虫なんかじゃない
I'm not a coward
自信ありげに PEACE SIGN
Confidence in a PEACE SIGN
君の瞳にキスして
Kiss your eyes
笑いたい 絶対 笑いたい
I want to laugh, I absolutely want to laugh
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to 陽気な Baby
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to cheerful Baby
JOY to JOY to JOY to ハッピーな SAY YEAH
JOY to JOY to JOY to HAPPY SAY YEAH
君の心もそう もっと DO-DO
Your heart too, more DO-DO
僕の心もそう いっそ GO-GO
My heart too, rather GO-GO
はじけてるんじゃない？ It's JOYFUL PA-PI-PU-PE-PO-PA-PU
Aren't we bursting? It's JOYFUL PA-PI-PU-PE-PO-PA-PU
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to 陽気な Baby
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to cheerful Baby
JOY to JOY to JOY to ハッピーな People
JOY to JOY to JOY to HAPPY People
ドキドキしちゃうの なぜだどう？
Why is my heart beating so fast?
ゾクゾクしちゃうの なぜだどう？
Why am I getting shivers?
この指に止まるのはどんな運命なんだ 全部知りたいな
What kind of fate will land on this finger? I want to know everything
じょいふるだって 終わっちゃう
Even being joyful comes to an end
Everybody きっと 終わっちゃう
Everybody, it will surely end
いついつまでも この時も 最終形態はきっと 修正なしで
Forever and ever, even this moment, the final form will surely be without correction
DO WE DO WE DO WE DO DO...
PA-PI-PU-PE-PO-PA-PI-PU-PE-TIME!
JOY TO JOY TO JOY TO POP NA BABY
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to 陽気な Baby
I wanna JOY to JOY to JOY to cheerful Baby
JOY to JOY to JOY to ハッピーな SAY YEAH
JOY to JOY to JOY to HAPPY SAY YEAH
君の心もそう もっと DO-DO
Your heart too, more DO-DO
僕の心もそう いっそ GO-GO
My heart too, rather GO-GO
はじけてるんじゃない？ It's JOYFUL PA-PI-PU-PE-PO-PA-PU
Aren't we bursting? It's JOYFUL PA-PI-PU-PE-PO-PA-PU
JOY! JOY! JOY! JOY! JOY! JOY! JOY! JOY!
JOY!
ラミィちゃん、おめでとうー！
Lamy-chan, congratulations!
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
（笑い声）
(Laughter)
おめでとうだね。
Congratulations.
頑張った、頑張った。
We did it, we did it.
みんな、みんな頑張ったー！
Everyone, everyone did their best!
ということで。
And so.
「じょいふる」、OKBRのメンバーで歌わせていただきましたー！
We performed 'JOYFUL' as the members of OKBR!
よし、じゃあ撮るかー！
Alright, let's take a photo!
待って、待って、待って！お疲れ全開のラミィ待って。
Wait, wait, wait! Hold on, Lamy, you're exhausted.
まだ、まだ、まだ。待って！
Wait, wait, not yet. Just wait!
何、何やりたいの？
What, what do you want to do?
ちょっと待って、まずは深呼吸させて……。
Wait a second, let me catch my breath first...
えーということで。
Alright, so.
本日ラミィ、実は今日誕生日なので。
Since today is actually Lamy's birthday.
そうね、おめでとう！とんでもない事実、そう、おめでとうございます。
That's right, happy birthday! An incredible fact, yes, congratulations.
なのでね、ちょっとやっぱり記念に、この汗だく記念に写真を撮りたいなと。
So, to commemorate this, this sweaty moment, I'd like to take a photo.
どういうポーズで撮りたい？
What kind of pose do you want to do?
あ、でもこれほら、せっかく今、後ろにキッズもみんな良い感じにいるから。
Ah, but look, the kids in the back are all lined up nicely right now.
これでやってみようか。
Let's try doing it like this.
この辺から？こう？
From around here? Like this?
あ、良いんじゃない？
Oh, that's good!
もうちょい近い方が良い？
Should we be a bit closer?
どうだ？良い感じ、良い感じ。
How's that? It looks good, looks good.
良い感じ？良いねー。
Looking good? Nice.
よし、変える、変える！待って、待って！
Alright, changing, changing! Wait, wait!
じゃあ、あと一個だけ！あと一個だけ！
Okay, just one more! Just one more!
あれやろうかな、これよ！
Maybe I'll do that, this one!
あれな、中中なんたら。
That Chu-chu thingy.
良いよ、良い？
Sure, okay?
じゃあラミィの掛け声で、我々は出発するでな！
Then, on my cue, we'll head out!
えーじゃあ何で？OKBRで行こうか、OK？
Alright, then what should we say? Let's go with OKBR, okay?
本当に行くよ、OKBRーー！！
I'm really doing it, OKBRRR!!
ママ、何あれ、見ちゃいけません。
Mama, what was that? You shouldn't look.
……夢落ち？
...Was it a dream?
常闇トワ先輩に来てもらいましたー！
Tokoyami Towa-senpai has joined us!
ありがとうー！そして、ラミィお誕生日おめでとう！
Thank you! And, Lamy, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
それじゃあみんな盛り上がっていくぞー！
Now then, everyone, let's get hyped!
いけないボーダーライン
Ikenai Borderline
見つめ合って 恋をして
Gazing at each other, falling in love
無我夢中で 追いかけて
Chasing frantically
だけど もっと 知りたくて メラメラしてる
But wanting to know more, I'm burning up
願うほど 謎が増え
The more I wish, the more mysteries increase
思うほど 熱になる
The more I think, the hotter I get
だから もっと 飛び込むの 未開の世界
So I'll dive further into the unexplored world
恋とか夢とか誰でも信じるけど
Anyone would believe in things like love or dreams
そこそこ攻めなきゃつまんないよ
But it's boring unless you take some risks
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Love on the edge, the forbidden borderline
難易度Gでも 全て壊してみせる
Even if it's Rank G difficulty, I'll break through it all
ギリギリ舞 さらなるGへと
Dancing on the edge, towards an even higher G
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
Consciousness melts, my body is out of control
いっちゃうかもね
I might just let go
ふざけあった友達と
With the friends I joked around with
求めあったあの人と
With the person I longed for
また会える日のために ギラギラしてる
I'm shining bright for the day we meet again
光るほど 影はでき
The brighter the light, the darker the shadow
燃えるほど 灰になる
The more I burn, the more I turn to ash
走るほど 見えてくる 危ないライン
The more I run, the more the dangerous line appears
自由も平和も　望めば生まれるけど
Freedom and peace are born if you wish for them
モタモタしてたら　腐っちゃうよ
But if you hesitate, they'll rot away
ギリギリ愛　危ないボーダーライン
Giri giri eye, dangerous borderline
非常識だね　まだ加速しているよ
It's insane, it's still accelerating
ギリギリ舞い　限界点なら
Giri giri dance, if it's the limit
塗り替えていい　破壊と再生から
It's okay to repaint, from destruction and rebirth
私ができる...
What I can do...
ギリギリ愛　いけないボーダーライン
Giri giri eye, forbidden borderline
難易度Gでも　すべて壊してみせる
Even with difficulty G, I'll show you I can break it all
ギリギリ舞い　さらなる次元へと
Giri giri dance, to a further dimension
意識が溶ける　体は制御不能
Consciousness melts, body is out of control
いっちゃうかもね
I might just go there
ギリギリ愛　いけないボーダーライン
Giri giri eye, forbidden borderline
燃え尽きながら　まだ輝いてみせる
While burning out, I'll still show you I can shine
ギリギリ舞い　あなたのために
Giri giri dance, for you
未来のために　何度砕け散っても
For the future, no matter how many times I'm shattered
愛することでき... 生まれ変わる
By being able to love... I'm reborn
愛されたくて... 生きている
Wanting to be loved... I'm living
はい、ということで常先輩に来ていただきました！
Alright, and so, we have Towa-senpai here with us!
イエーイ！やってきちゃったぜ！イエイイエイイエイ！
Yay! I'm here! Yay yay yay!
あ、もう...
Ah, already...
いいですね、こういうやっぱり明るい先輩がいてくれるって、助かるな〜
It's great, having such a bright senior here really helps out~
私、出しきっちゃったわ、ホ〜！
I've given it my all, whoo!
今回ですね、常先輩をちょっとお呼びさせて頂いて、お誘いさせて頂いたのには、実は理由がありまして
There's actually a reason why I invited and asked Towa-senpai to join me this time
理由？めちゃめちゃ丁寧な言葉遣い。いいよ。
Reason? Such very polite language. Go ahead.
いや、あの、七夕の時、覚えてます？
Well, do you remember back at Tanabata?
七夕の時？
Tanabata?
七夕の短冊に何、なんて自分で書かれたか覚えてます？
Do you remember what you wrote on your Tanabata strip?
待って、なんて書いたっけ？超忘れた。でも、何かを出した気はする。
Wait, what did I write? I totally forgot. But I feel like I submitted something.
え、なんて書いてた？
What was written?
え、色んなホロメンと歌が歌いたいって。
Uh, that you wanted to sing songs with various Holomembers.
おお〜！
Oh~!
え、これ違ってたらどうしよう...
Wait, what if I'm wrong...
あれ？書いたっけ？
Huh? Did I write that?
でも、それはでも、したいなっていうのはあったから... あ、それを叶えてくれたってこと？
But, well, it was something I wanted to do... Oh, so you're making it come true?
いや、これは、これをその時に、実は歌いたいなって思ってたんですけど、なかなかお誘いするきっかけがなくて
Well, I actually wanted to sing then, but I didn't really have the chance to invite you
なくて！
Didn't!
そう、で、あ、誕生日ライブ！常先輩！と思って！
Right, and then I thought, "Birthday Live! Towa-senpai!"
お〜！皆さん、呼ばれちゃいました。常闇トワです。
Oh~! Everyone, I've been called upon. I'm Tokoyami Towa.
実際にこうやって、えっと... ごめんなさい、スルーしちゃって。
Actually, doing this... sorry, I skipped over that.
いいよいいよ、全然いいよ。
It's fine, it's totally fine.
実際にラミィと、ちょっと初めて歌う形になったんですけれども
It's actually the first time I'm singing with Lamy like this, but
はい。
Yes.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
あんたいろんな声、声持ってんな。
You've got so many different voices.
え、嬉しい。
Oh, I'm happy.
かっこいいよ、今日。
You're cool today.
なんで急にちょっと...
Why all of a sudden...
可愛いのもうたえるし、かっこいいのも歌えるって、めちゃめちゃもう武器やないかーい！
Being able to sing cute songs and cool songs too, that's quite the weapon, isn't it!
えへへ。
Ehehe.
テンション尖ってんなー。
Your energy is really sharp.
やっぱこうやって、なんだかんだこう二人でコラボするっていうのもあまりなかったから
After all, we haven't really had many chances to collab just the two of us like this
確かに、なかったかもしれない。
True, maybe we haven't.
4人とかはあったけど。
We've had 4-person ones though.
そう、4人はね、何回かある。
Right, we've had 4-person ones a few times.
ふたりは... やっぱ気まずいから、今後やめるか。
Just the two of us... is awkward after all, so shall we stop from now on?
なんでだよ！気まずくない、何も気まずくないじゃんよ！
Why?! It's not awkward, it's not awkward at all!
ね、ほら、その仲の良さをアピールする写真撮りましょうよ。
Look, let's take a photo to show off how well we get along.
あ、いいよ。あ、こっち行くわ。じゃあ。
Ah, sure. I'll go over here then.
いいよ。
Okay.
ちょっと二枚くらい撮ろうか。
Let's take about two photos.
二枚。どんなポーズがいい？
Two. What kind of pose should we do?
え、なんか可愛い、あ、かっこいいの方。いけないボーダーラインっぽい感じで。
Uh, something cute, ah, the cool one. Like "Ikenai Borderline" style.
あ、一枚目だけってこと？一枚、え、ん？
Oh, you mean just for the first one? One, uh, hmm?
二枚撮るから。
We're taking two.
可愛いのから行かない？
Shall we start with a cute one?
え、可愛い、ね、それ可愛い。撮るよ、可愛い。
Oh, cute, yeah, that's cute. I'm taking it, cute.
あ、可愛い！
Ah, cute!
お、可愛い、可愛い。
Oh, cute, cute.
かっこよくない？
Isn't it cool?
あ、かっこいい！
Ah, it's cool!
ま、お前も可愛いよ
Well, you're cute too.
あ、ありがとう
Ah, thank you.
ちゃんと後輩も褒めるからな
Since you also properly praise your juniors.
あの、サムネイルのさ、
Um, the thumbnail...
お、これも、これもやろうよ
Oh, let's do this, let's do this too.
おーいいよいいよ
Oh, okay, okay.
この綺麗な美しい
This clean, beautiful...
そうそうそうそう
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
ということで、トワ先輩、
So, Towa-senpai,
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
イエーイ
Yay!
ハッピーバースデー
Happy Birthday.
カラフル
Colorful
作詞・作曲：渡辺翔
Lyrics/Composition: Sho Watanabe
いつもモノクロだった
It was always monochrome
瞳の奥の
In the depths of my eyes
景色捨てたら
If I throw away the scenery
夢見つけた
I found a dream
何もない世界で
In a world where there's nothing
作る絆は
The bonds we create
強い意志与えた
Gave me a strong will
動き出した
It started moving
日常の中で
Within daily life
走ってゆく先に
At the end of running
君がいた
You were there
触れた心が輝いた
The heart I touched shone
鮮やかな虹になって
Becoming a vivid rainbow
羽ばたくよ希望を乗せて
I'll flap my wings, carrying hope
無限に広がる空の下
Under the infinitely expanding sky
集まった願い守り進めばほら
If we protect and move forward with the gathered wishes, look
まだ誰も知らない明日へと
To a tomorrow that no one knows yet
引き寄せられるように
As if being drawn in
覗いた瞬間
The moment I peeked
光の糸は君包んだ
The thread of light wrapped around you
解き散らしたような
As if unraveled and scattered
絡まった運命
Entangled destiny
一歩また変われる
One step, I can change again
間違えても信じた道が
Even if I make a mistake, the path I believed in
新しい景色を照らすだろう
Will probably illuminate a new scenery
巡る時の中で笑って
Smiling within the turning time
様々な想い持って
With various thoughts
始めようまた一から
Let's start again from one
辿り着いた儚い軌跡
The fleeting trajectory we reached
壊れないように手を伸ばし繋げばほら
If we reach out and connect our hands so they don't break, look
君はそばでいつまでも
You'll be by my side forever
また透明な私たちは
We, who are transparent again
どんな色にでも染まることができるから
Because we can be dyed in any color
夢叶えよう
Let's make our dreams come true
走っていく先に君はいた
At the end of running, you were there
触れた心が輝いた
The heart I touched shone
鮮やかな虹になって
Becoming a vivid rainbow
羽ばたくよ希望を乗せて
I'll flap my wings, carrying hope
無限に広がる空の下
Under the infinitely expanding sky
集まった願い守り行けば
If we go protecting the gathered wishes
君と誓ったあの日の希望を
That day's hope I promised you
今超えて過去からまた
Crossing it now, from the past again
誰も知らない明日へと
To a tomorrow no one knows
ちょ、ちょっと...
Wait, wait a second...
いきなりそんな遠く行かないで！
Don't move away so suddenly!
そ、そうだよね。
R-Right, you're right.
そうでっす。
Exactly.
皆さん、ちょっとこの微妙な空気...
Everyone, can you feel this...
わかるでしょうか？
...slightly awkward atmosphere?
微妙、微妙な空気じゃないですよ！
Awkward? It's not awkward at all!
天音かなた先輩です！ありがとうございます！
It's Amane Kanata-senpai! Thank you!
お邪魔します。ラミィちゃん、お誕生日...
Pardon the intrusion. Lamy-tan, happy...
おめでとう！
...birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いやなんかね、ちょっとみんな、あ...
Well, I think everyone might be like...
どういう感じ？って感じかもしれないですけど。
"What's this vibe?" but...
ちょっとね、困惑してるんじゃないですか？
They might be a bit confused, right?
この空気にね。あのー...
By this atmosphere. Um...
これはですね、わかってます。
Well, the thing is, we know.
僕たちもね、あーもう...
We've already...
とうにリハも何度もやって...
...done rehearsals many times...
今よりもっとね、気まずいトークを...
...and repeated talks even more...
何度も繰り返し...
...awkward than this one...
さすがにこれは、友達の友達代に...
As expected, this is the limit for...
なみおんな、とか言って...
..."friends of friends" for 5 years...
もういいよ！あのー...
That's enough! Um...
今回ね、ちょっと距離感を感じたから...
Since we felt some distance this time...
これ、2回目のMCになっております。
...this is actually our second MC segment.
もうちょっと、あの、NGの理由が...
The reason for the redo was because...
MCに距離があるからっていう...
...there was distance in the MC...
いや、そんなことない！仲良し！
No, that's not it! We're close!
仲良しですよ！
We're close friends!
ということで今日は、本当に...
So, today I really...
かなた先輩と「カラフル」が歌いたくて。
...wanted to sing "Colorful" with Kanata-senpai.
いやもう本当にね、嬉しかった。
I was really happy about that.
誘ってもらった時嬉しくて。でも...
I was happy when you invited me. But...
この「カラフル」っていう曲は、僕...
Actually, I didn't know...
知らなかったのね。
...this song "Colorful."
え、そうなんですか？！
Wait, really?!
そう。今回のために...
Yes. Just for this occasion...
覚えました！
...I learned it!
いや、あの、かなた先輩、今回すごい...
Wow, Kanata-senpai added so...
たくさん、ハモリを...
...many harmonies this time...
そうだね。ちょっとね。
I did. A little bit.
オリジナルで入れてくださったんですよ！
She added her own original ones!
今日、気分が乗ってて。
I was feeling motivated today.
この微妙、微妙な空気...
Despite this awkward atmosphere...
知らなかったんですか？！
You didn't even know the song?!
知らない曲で...
I didn't know it, but...
覚えてから、今日が乗り始めて。
...after I learned it, I got really into it.
ハモリ足していい？もっと入れたい、とか言って。
I asked, "Can I add harmonies? I want more."
今日、ハモリをね、あのー...
She added harmonies for me...
入れてくださったんですよね！
...all throughout today's performance!
いれさせていただきました。
I took the liberty of doing so.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ねー、せっかく2回目なんで...
Since we're doing a second take...
微妙な空気... そんなことないですよ！
Awkward atmosphere? Not at all!
仲良し撮影会しましょう！
Let's take some photos as close friends!
あ、そうだね。撮影会を。
Ah, good idea. Let's do that.
はい。
Okay.
仲良しですよ！
We're close friends!
いいんじゃない？あ、いいじゃないですか！
This is good, right? Oh, it's great!
後ろのイラストも相まって、可愛い、可愛い。
With the illustration behind us, it's so cute.
あ、いい感じいい感じ。
Yeah, looking good.
5年後、連絡取ってなさそうなんだよね。
It looks like we won't be in contact in 5 years.
えー？！取ってよ！取ってるよね？！
What?! Stay in touch! We will, right?!
取ってるよね？大丈夫だよ、一生の...
We will, right? It's fine, we're friends for...
一生の友達になるかもしれないから。
...we might be friends for life.
ちょっとわかんない...
Well, I don't know about that...
なんでだよ！そこはさぁ！
Why are you like that?! Come on!
踏んでよ！
Just go with it!
そこ、そこまでは、ちょっとまだ、あれだけど...
Well, maybe not that far yet, but...
これからね！
From now on!
そうだね！どんどんね！
Right! Bit by bit!
どんどん仲良く...
Becoming closer and closer...
なっていきますよね？！なりますなります！
...right?! Yes, we will! Definitely!
なります、なります。
We will, we will.
なんなの、この友達の友達感。
What's with this "friend of a friend" vibe?
そんなことないですよ！
It's not like that at all!
ということでじゃあ、えー、次のゲストに行きます！
Anyway, let's move on to the next guest!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ビジネスフレンド...
Business friend...
やめろ！
Stop it!
それでは、ここまでたくさんの...
Well, I've performed with...
ゲストの方たちと歌ってきましたが...
...many guests so far, but...
やっぱりね、最後はラミィの大好きな...
...at the end, I'd like to sing with...
あの3人と歌を歌いたいなと...
...my three favorite people...
思います！
...if that's okay!
それでは呼んでいきましょう！
Let's call them out!
ししろーん！
Shishiro-on!
うぇーい！
Ueeeii!
ポルかまるー！
Polka-maru!
あ、はーい！
Ah, yes!
どうも、尾丸ポルカです！
Hello, I'm Omaru Polka!
いえーい！楽しかったね、さっき。
Yay! That was fun earlier, wasn't it?
ねねねー！
Nene-ne!
ということでじゃあ、ちょっとぎゅっとして...
All right, let's get together...
ということで！
And now!
ぎゅっとして！
Gather 'round!
私たち、
We are...
ね！ぽ！ら！ぼ！です！
Ne! Po! La! Bo! Desu!
練習してなかったわりに上手いね！
That was surprisingly good for no practice!
上手い！今のタイミングよかったね！
It was! The timing was perfect!
よく決まったね！
We nailed it!
いいじゃん、じゃあもう、これで今日は...
Great. So, for today...
あれ？呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Wait. Thanks for inviting us!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
おめでとう！お誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy Birthday!
今一瞬忘れてたでしょ？
You guys forgot for a second, didn't you?
なんでー？！
No, why would you say that?!
決まったことに気を取られて、ちょっと忘れ...
I was too focused on the timing, I just...
今、ちょうどよかったなー、と思って。
I was just thinking, "That was perfect."
いや、それが一番よかったんですよ！
No, that was actually the best part!
嬉しいよね、誕生日にみんなが来てくれて。
I'm so happy everyone came for my birthday.
嬉しいよ、ありがとう！
I'm so glad, thank you!
で、なんでここに私たちは？
So, why are we here exactly?
というかここはどこだ？どこだ？
And where is this place? Where?
そう、みんなね、ちょっと見慣れないかなーって...
Right, I thought it might look unfamiliar...
思うんだけど...
...to everyone, but...
実はこちらは...
Actually, this place is...
尾丸ポルカサーカス！
...the Omaru Polka Circus!
あ、私のやつ？！
Wait, my place?!
え、そうなの？！
Oh, really?!
そうなんです。全然イメージがちょっと...
Yes. Although the image is completely...
違うかもしれないけど。
...different, perhaps.
いや、こんなんあったかなぁ。
Wow, did it always look like this?
あなたの所だからここ
This is your place.
すごいね、でもえっこんな感じで改装してくれたの？ラミィ
Amazing. But did you renovate it like this, Lamy?
改装…改装したわけじゃないけど、なんかもう消すものを消してみて…
Renovated... it's not like I renovated it, but I just removed things that needed to be removed...
なるほどね
I see.
そして電気を、電気を消すだけで…
And just by turning off the lights...
断捨離、断捨離
Decluttering, decluttering.
電気をね、消して…明日からボロ隠しが目立つようになります
Turning off the lights... from tomorrow, the wear and tear will stand out.
いい雰囲気にしました。ありがとうございます、綺麗にしてくださって
I made a nice atmosphere. Thank you for making it beautiful.
えっ、ここに何をするんだい？
Eh, what are we going to do here?
ここで、うん、四人で
Here, yeah, with the four of us.
えっ？
Eh?
まあそうだよな
Well, that's right.
初めて、はい、歌を歌いたいなと思います
For the first time, yes, I'd like us to sing a song.
やったー！イエーイ！
Hooray! Yay!
じゃあ初めてね、四人で歌う歌ね
So, for the first time, a song the four of us sing.
記念だしな。何歌うの？何歌うの？
It's a commemoration. What are we singing? What are we singing?
えっとね、みんなが好きな歌で
Well, it's a song that everyone likes.
ラミィたちがデビューしたのは何月ですか？はい、ねねさん
What month did Lamy and the others debut? Yes, Nene-san.
八月であります！
It's August!
ピンポン！正解であります！
Ding-dong! Correct!
そう、八月が関係している歌をみんなでね、歌っていきたいなと
Yes, I want us all to sing a song related to August.
何だろう？えっ、みんな知ってる曲かな？
I wonder what it is? Eh, is it a song everyone knows?
えっ、みんな知ってる。好きよ、好きだと思う。好きか？
Eh, everyone knows it. You'll like it, I think you'll like it. Do you?
じゃあ俺じゃダメか？ダメか…
Then, is it no good if it's "ore"? No good...
俺でいいか？
Is "ore" okay?
おまえらに届けるぜ
I'll deliver it to you guys!
歌声、俺たちの歌声届けるぜ
Our singing voice, we'll deliver our singing voice!
届けるぜ。そうだね、じゃあ四人で届けていきましょうか
Deliver it. That's right, so let's deliver it with the four of us.
はい！
Yes!
それでは聞いてください。secret base ～君がくれたもの～
Now, please listen. secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~.
secret base ～君がくれたもの～ 作詞・作曲 町田 紀彦
secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~ / Lyrics & Music: Norihiko Machida
君と夏の終わり　将来の夢
You and the end of summer, our dreams for the future
大きな希望　忘れない
Those big hopes, I won't forget them
10年後の8月　また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
最高の思い出を…
Our best memories...
出会いはふっとした瞬間に
Our meeting was at a sudden moment
帰り道の交差点で
At the intersection on the way home
声をかけてくれたね　「一緒に帰ろう」
You called out to me, "Let's go home together"
僕は照れくさそうに　カバンで顔隠しながら
Embarrassed, I hid my face with my bag
本当はとってもとっても嬉しかったよ
But actually, I was very, very happy
あぁ　花火が夜空　綺麗に咲いて　ちょっと切なく
Ah, the fireworks bloomed beautifully in the night sky, feeling a bit bittersweet
あぁ　風が時間と共に流れる
Ah, the wind flows along with time
嬉しくて　楽しくて　冒険も色々したね
So happy, so fun, we went on many adventures
二人の秘密基地の中
Inside our secret base
君と夏の終わり　将来の夢　大きな希望　忘れない
You and the end of summer, our dreams for the future, those big hopes, I won't forget them
10年後の8月　また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
君が最後まで心から　「ありがとう」叫んでたこと知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the end
涙をこらえて　笑顔でさよなら　切ないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile, it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
Our best memories...
あぁ　夏休みも　あと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, because summer vacation is almost over
あぁ　太陽と月　仲良くして
Ah, sun and moon, get along well
悲しくて　寂しくて　喧嘩も色々したね
So sad, so lonely, we had many fights, too
二人の秘密基地の中
Inside our secret base
君が最後まで心から　「ありがとう」叫んでたこと知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the end
涙をこらえて　笑顔でさよなら　切ないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile, it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
Our best memories...
突然の…
The sudden...
転校で…
...transfer...
どうしようもなく…
...that there was nothing we could do...
...をしようよ
...let's share a secret
電話もするよ
I'll call you too
忘れないでね
Don't forget
僕のことを
About me
いつまでも
Forever
二人の基地の中
Inside our secret base
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
The end of summer with you, talking for so long
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
Watching the sunset and then looking at the stars
君の頬を流れた 涙はずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears that ran down your cheeks
君が最後まで
You, until the very end
大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
Waving your hand so widely, I'll surely never forget it
だからこうして 夢の中で
That's why, like this, in my dreams
ずっと永遠に...
Forever and ever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, our dreams for the future
大きな希望 忘れない
Big hopes, I won't forget
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
君が最後まで
You, until the very end
心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart
涙をこらえて
Holding back the tears
笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Saying goodbye with a smile, it's painful, isn't it?
最高の
The best
思い出を...
Memories...
最高の
The best
思い出を...
Memories...
それはとっても キラキラ眩しくて
It was so sparkly and dazzling.
私もあんな風になれたらって
I wish I could be like that too.
すごかった
That was amazing
よいしょ
Heave-ho
お名前 雪花ラミィ
Name: Yukihana Lamy
えっと、生年月日、志望動機、送信！
Let's see, date of birth, reason for applying, Send!
よし
Alright
お願いします
Please
あ、あっ！
Ah, ah!
歌は得意ですか？
Are you good at singing?
えーっと...
Well...
GOOD!
お願いします
Please
審議中...
Under deliberation...
ようこそホロライブへ！
Welcome to hololive!
やったー！やりました、だいふく！やりました！
I did it! I did it, Daifuku! I did it!
皆さんお待ちかねです では参りましょう、あなたのライブステージへ！
Everyone is waiting for you. Let's go to your live stage!
みんなの前で歌う...
Singing in front of everyone...
私なんかが...
Someone like me...
えっ？
Eh?
LiveStage Start!!
待って、待ってください！待って、まだ私...
Wait, please wait! Wait, I'm still...
踏み出す勇気、持てなかった
I didn't have the courage to step forward.
スノードロップ。どんな時も、強く、美しく。
Snowdrop. Always strong and beautiful.
私だって...
I too...
みんな...
Everyone...
よし
Alright.
お父様、お母様、
Father, Mother,
私、
I...
行ってきます
I'm off.
うわあ！
Whoa!
ドアを開けてください！
Please open the door!
くっ、
Ugh,
うわああ！
Whoaaa!
うわあああああ！
Whoaaaaaaaa!
うわあ！
Whoa!
はっ！
Ha!
お待ちしておりました 雪花ラミィさん、
We've been waiting for you, Yukihana Lamy,
さあ、あなたのステージへ！！
Now, to your stage!!
うわあ！
Whoa!
それでは、
And now,
聞いてください。
please listen.
明日への境界線
The Borderline to Tomorrow.
夢の数だけ夢は
They say dreams grow larger
大きくなるんだって
for every dream you have.
小さな頃から
I should have known that
知ってたはず
ever since I was small.
心がブレーキかけて
Even if my heart puts on the brakes
立ち止まってしまっても
and I come to a standstill,
ゴールは逃げたりしないから
the goal won't run away.
一歩ずつ ゆっくりでも
Step by step, even if it's slowly.
一歩ずつ 前だけ見て
Step by step, just looking forward.
辛くても
Even if it's hard,
絶対に諦めない
I will never give up.
だって大切な仲間がいつもそばにいるから
Because precious friends are always by my side.
行くよ！
Let's go!
明日への境界線を
The borderline to tomorrow,
みんなでせーの、超えたい
everyone, on three, let's cross it.
繋がる絆は離れない
Connected bonds won't separate.
空回りが雨降らし
Spinning my wheels brings rain,
つまずくこともあるけど
though I might stumble sometimes.
精一杯
With all my might,
大丈夫
it's okay.
今日と仲間を信じて進め
Believe in today and your friends and move forward.
絆が深まるほど
As bonds deepen,
夢は確信に変わる
dreams turn into certainty.
素敵な未来を描こうね
Let's draw a wonderful future.
一歩ずつ 怖がらずに
Step by step, without being afraid.
一歩ずつ 空見上げて
Step by step, looking up at the sky.
暗闇も
Even the darkness
いつかは晴れるからね
will clear up someday.
道に迷って落ち込む私を照らしてくれる
Shining a light on me when I lose my way and feel down.
行くよ！
Let's go!
夢との境界線へ
To the borderline with dreams,
みんなでせーの、飛び込もう
everyone, on three, let's dive in.
想いを繋げて未来まで
Connect our feelings until the future.
遠回りだぜ吹かし
Taking a detour and revving up,
倒れることもあるけど
though I might fall down sometimes.
ずっと
Forever
一緒だよ
we're together.
さあ描いた夢まで進め
Now, move forward to the dream we drew.
明日への境界線を
The borderline to tomorrow,
みんなでせーの、超えたい
everyone, on three, let's cross it.
繋がる絆は離れない
Connected bonds won't separate.
どんな未来が待ってても
No matter what future awaits,
必ず隣にいるよ
I'll definitely be by your side.
どうか
Please
忘れないで
don't forget.
さあ明日を迎えに行こう
Now, let's go meet tomorrow.
雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2021、11月15日21時から発売開始します。
Yukihana Lamy Birthday Celebration 2021 will go on sale starting from November 15th at 9:00 PM.
今回の誕生日記念フルセットは、記念ボイス1種、記念グッズが3種類。
This time's Birthday Celebration Full Set includes one type of commemorative voice and three types of commemorative goods.
フルセット購入特典はなんと、ラミィ直筆サイン入り箔押し複製メッセージポストカードとなっております。
The full set purchase bonus is, amazingly, a foil-stamped duplicate message postcard with Lamy's autograph.
フルセットお迎えしてくれた方全員に直筆サインを入れるので、慌てないでゆっくり注文してね。
I'll be autographing them for everyone who gets the full set, so please take your time and order without rushing.
それでは商品紹介です。まず記念ボイスは、
Now for the product introduction. First, the commemorative voice is
おはようからおやすみまで、いろんな場面で使えるシステムボイスのセット。
a set of system voices you can use in various situations, from good morning to good night.
そして記念グッズはねこみ先生描き下ろしのラバーマット。
And the commemorative goods are a rubber mat illustrated by Necomi-sensei.
サイズは高さ34cm、幅60cm。パソコンのマウスパッドやカードゲームのマットにも使えちゃうサイズです。
The size is 34cm high and 60cm wide. It's a size that can also be used as a PC mousepad or a card game mat.
そして、高さ23cm、幅16.6cmの等身大大福ぬいぐるみ。
And, a life-size Daifuku plushie, 23cm high and 16.6cm wide.
もっちもちの素材を使っているので、たくさん抱きしめてね。
It's made of a squishy material, so please give it lots of hugs.
最後は雪民ステンレスタンブラー。
Finally, the Yukimin Stainless Tumbler.
雪民さんがいっぱい散りばめられた可愛いタンブラーになっています。
It's a cute tumbler with many Yukimin scattered all over it.
大福もいるので、ぜひぜひ見つけてみてね。
Daifuku is there too, so please try to find him.
今回も細かい部分までこだわったグッズになっていますので、
These goods were designed with great attention to detail again this time,
みんなお迎えしてくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if everyone could welcome them home.
最後に、ちょっと恥ずかしいけど、
Lastly, it's a bit embarrassing, but
今日は雪民さんに手紙を書いてきました。
I've written a letter to the Yukimin today.
今日はラミィのために最後まで見守ってくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for watching over Lamy until the very end today.
雪民さん、大好きだよ。
Yukimin, I love you.
（チュッ）
(Mwah)
大好きな雪民さんへ♡
To my beloved Yukimin ♡
いつも温かい声援、笑い、こだわり、たくさん愛を伝えてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always giving me warm support, laughter, your dedication, and for sharing so much love with me!
君がいたから、ここまでこれたよ！！
Because you were here, I was able to make it this far!!
これからもずっとずっと一緒にいようね！！
Let's stay together forever and ever!!
だいすきっ！！
I love you!!
2021.11.15 雪花ラミィ
2021.11.15 Yukihana Lamy
LIVEどうだったー！？
How was the LIVE!?